(647) 865-3991 Oshawa, Ontario hello@devyratnasari.com

Devy Ratnasari

Data Analyst / Data Scientist / Programmer

linkedin.com/in/devy-ratnasari github.com/devyratnasari devyratnasari.com

Skilled and results-driven professional with two years of experience in software development with a focus on designing and building an end-user application. Successfully improve the efficiency of the business process. Independently managed, designed and implemented business processes for the company. Awarded recognition for excellent company performance. Viewed as a strong problem solver in intense and demanding environments.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Programming Python, C#, Java, FlaskAPI, SQL, Mysql, SQLAlchemy

Artificial Intelligence Machine Learning, Deep Learning, OpenCV, TensorFlow, Scikit-Learn

Visualisation Tools Tableau, PowerBI

Cloud AWS EC2, Azure (Fundamentals), Heroku

Application Visual Studio, Jupyter Notebook

PROJECTS

Canada Government Proactive Disclosure Travel Expenses

August 2023 — August 2023

- Conducted Extract, Transform, Load (ETL) processes on raw travel expense data to ensure data accuracy and prepare it for meaningful analysis.
- Leveraged a BERTopic model to effectively classify and categorize travel expenses based on their purposes, enhancing data organization and analysis.
- Designed interactive Tableau visualizations to visually represent insights from the Canadian Government's Proactive Disclosure of travel expenses, thereby promoting transparency and accountability.
- Implemented advanced features in Tableau, such as filters, parameters, and calculated fields, to empower users to customize their data exploration experience and extract valuable insights.
- Contributed to the government's decision-making process by transforming raw data into actionable information through data profiling, classification, and visualization.
- Details: https://devyratnasari.com/visual/can-gov-travel.html

Human Resources Executive Dashboard

August 2023 — August 2023

- Designed and developed a robust Human Resources Executive Dashboard aimed at monitoring performance metrics and workforce trends.
- Leveraged technology like Tableau to create interactive visualizations, providing executives with real-time insights into critical aspects of HR, including recruitment, employee engagement, and retention metrics.
- Implemented engaging filters and slicers within the dashboard to empower users to explore HR data from various angles, such as by department, tenure, and other relevant dimensions.
- Streamlined HR data management and reporting, facilitating data-driven decision-making processes within the organization.
- Enhanced transparency and accessibility of HR metrics, ensuring that executives have the necessary tools to make informed strategic decisions.
- Details: https://devyratnasari.com/visual/HRA-exec-dash.html

Automatic Attendance Using Face Recognition and Object Detection (Capstone Project)

May 2022 — August 2022

- Constructed a web application for collecting students' attendance using facial recognition. This application could simplify the lecturer's task in taking attendance and calling out each student's name and reduce the possibility of other people taking attendance on behalf of someone else.
- Project: https://devyratnasari.com/cv/attendance.html

Credit Card Detection (Capstone Project)

January 2022 — April 2022

- Mapped and transformed data to a consistent uniform format.
- Validate data to ensure that data is accurate, reliable, and meets the required standards.
- Built a credit card fraud detection model using multiple Machine Learning and Deep Learning algorithms.
- IEEE presentation: Youtube presentation link | Analysis: https://devyratnasari.com/ml/capstone1.html

EDUCATION

Artificial Intelligence Analysis, Design & Implementation - Graduate Certificate

January 2022 — October 2022

Ontario, Canada

• Conduct research, data analysis, model development, and solution deployment in an ethical manner that protects privacy, and confidentiality, addresses data bias and transparency and ensures data integrity.

Computer Science - Bachelor Degree

September 2009 — April 2013

BINUS University

Jakarta, Indonesia

- Recognizes the new technology trends as the enablers of modern-day business analytics and intelligence for decision support.
- Analyze how organizations employ business intelligence (BI) to make decisions or gain a competitive edge.
- Identify Decision Support Opportunities that are supported by business analytics and intelligence.

(647) 865-3991 Oshawa, Ontario hello@devyratnasari.com

Devy Ratnasari

Data Analyst / Data Scientist / Programmer

linkedin.com/in/devy-ratnasari github.com/devyratnasari devyratnasari.com

TECHNICAL EXPERIENCE

IT Programmer

Agung Sedayu Group

August 2014 — July 2016

Jakarta, Indonesia

- Collaborated with cross-functional teams, including product managers and designers, to translate product requirements into technical specifications.
- Developed and maintained software applications with a focus on meeting product goals and functionality.
- Implemented and documented coding standards, enhancing the overall quality and maintainability of software projects.
- · Proactively identified and resolved technical issues, ensuring smooth workflow throughout the development life-cycle.

OTHER EXPERIENCE

Restaurant Manager

June 2020 — November 2021

Kuon Group

Sydney, Australia

- Achieved a remarkable 100% occupancy rate and drove significant sales growth during the pandemic by leveraging social media.
- Significantly enhanced the overall customer experience and contributed to substantial sales increases by designing and implementing a customer dictionary system.
- · Led team members of six that earned the prestigious Australian Good Food Guide award for excellence in food and service.

Human Resources Assistant

March 2013 — March 2014

Alila Hotels Jakarta

Jakarta, Indonesia

- Provided end-to-end administrative support for HR processes, from on-boarding to off-boarding, ensuring a seamless experience for employees.
- Demonstrated exceptional interpersonal skills while communicating with candidates, employees, and external contacts, fostering positive working relationships.
- Collaborated effectively with other HR team members, assisting in recruitment efforts, employee training, and maintaining personnel records.